Vinay Venkatareddy

Python - Backend Engineer

Personal Info

Address

Vancouver, BC Canada

Phone

226 700 2141

E-mail

vinaynv987@gmail.com

Hackerrank

https://www.hackerrank.com/vinaynv 987

Github

https://github.com/vinaynv3

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinayvenkatareddy/

Software/Programming Languages

Languages: Python, C/C++, SQL **Frameworks:** Python Django

Web Technologies: HTML/CSS, RESTful web API (Django rest framework), TCP/IP, HTTP, GraphQL

Database: SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite

Shell scripting Tools: Bash / Shell

Cloud Platform: Heroku (PaaS)

Version control system: Git & Github

Operating System: Linux (Ubuntu), Microsoft Windows server's

References

James Cloughley

Saransh Vaid

Dileep Nunna

Frol Shpak

S

Summary

- Software professional with 2+ years of experience in software design, analysis and troubleshooting software applications.
- Knowledge of Algorithms/Data structures, Software design patterns, Object-Oriented programming, proficient in scripting, coding and debugging.

Projects

Kleir - Document management solution for property valuation (appraisal service) companies

The above product provides solutions for small to mid-sized property valuation companies to store, manage & process appraisal service data.

Website developed using **Python Django** framework based on software design pattern called MVT, **Bootstrap** is used for Frontend, **HTML** for body content and user interaction and database is **SQLite3**

Deployment server: **Heroku** - https://kleir.herokuapp.com/ Version Control System: **Git & GitHub** - https://github.com/vinaynv3/kleir For more details on project, see link

- https://github.com/vinaynv3/kleir/blob/master/README.md

Work Experience

2019-01-2021-06

Software Support Analyst Microdea (now Transflo)

- Provided product support, information and assistance to IT administrators via web, email and phone
- Designed workflow automation solutions for Mircodea customer's using **python** and assisted team in researching solutions and troubleshooting product issues
- Maintained customer server's on Citrix cloud/on-premise by performing security checks, installed latest updates, review server physical state and backups, reduced server downtime
- Assisted business owners in identifying & cataloguing the required data from SQL Server databases and managed database storage, backups & recovery
- Maintained a high degree of customer service for all support queries and adhering to support department procedures and best practices

2018-08 -2018-12

Network Specialist - Intern TouchLogic

- Centralizing administrative tasks by improving scalability and workloads in servers through Virtualisation
- Successfully configured networks, servers, storage and managed resources on VMs and physical hardware using Hyper-V technology
- Maintained high availability in serves. Administered and automated infrastructure through Bash/Shell
- Understood importance of Documentation and Communication in SDLC process and disciplines followed in Agile Environment

Education

2016-01-2017-05 Post-Graduate Certificate in Software and Information Systems Testing, Fanshawe College, London, ON, Canada

2011-09 -2015-06 B.Engg in Computer Science and Engineering, Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, INDIA